okay I'm just gonna welcome to the
stream mr. John Kiriakou and hi John can
you hear me there he is hello how are
you hi I am so happy to see you thank
you so much for being here we're happy
to do it
oh absolutely fabulous we've had so many
people so excited that you're gonna be
here oh my pleasure John and we've just
been doing a little bit of an intro over
the last hour or so just explaining to
people who's going to be or who are
going to be on the stream but also what
the understanding and founding purpose
of this is for us which is that we have
brought together people from right
across the political sphere with
completely different political opinions
and affiliations because we are united
in this one single purpose of advocating
for the human rights the protection and
restoration of the human rights of
Julian Assange demanding his freedom
that he'd be allowed to realize his
asylum in Ecuador and also recognizing
the the threat to Julian and WikiLeaks
as a grave threat to press freedom so
I'd really like you to talk to us about
those issues tonight because you are a
whistleblower and whistleblowers are
dependent upon journalists to get their
messages out is that correct oh it's
absolutely correct you know especially
in the intelligence community here in
the United States we're taught when
we're first hired that if you see
evidence of waste fraud abuse or
illegality that you go through the chain
of command but time and time again it's
been proven that that just simply
doesn't work Tom Drake went through the
chain of command he was rewarded with
nine felony charges including seven
counts of espionage bill bini Kirk Wiebe
Diane Roark went through their chains of
command and and they were arrested and
harassed by the police I didn't go
through my chain of command because my
chain of command created the CIA's
torture program I went to the press and
so really
for me the only thing to do is to go to
the press would be whistleblowers he
mail me call me call me all the time I
get this all the time and people ask me
who in the media should they go to well
outlets like the New York Times The
Washington Post the intercept have
encryption keys on their websites I
don't trust any of them frankly and I
tell people every time I'm asked the
only place to go is WikiLeaks because
WikiLeaks is the only organization that
has never blown a source it's the only
organization you can trust to handle
this kind of information and it that was
true years ago with Chelsea Manning it's
true today
absolutely amazing point yes so then
conversely John what is the three you
know if we if we failed stand up for
Gillian we fail stand for WikiLeaks I
mean what is the wider impact of that
the wider impact is that there's
literally nowhere for a whistleblower to
go and so the information just doesn't
get out I can't tell you how many times
people have said to me that that they
just assess that it's not worth going
forward so they just keep their mouth
shut
and you know the the country is is
lesser for it here in the United States
especially with national security
whistleblowers I believe very firmly
that the American people own that
information the information belongs to
the people the citizens of the United
States not to the people who classified
it it's also illegal in the United
States to classify something that is a
crime it's illegal to classify something
so that it doesn't see the light of day
so that it can't go public well that
still happens every day and the only
reason we know about it is because of
whistleblowers well if there's no outlet
for a whistleblower to go to then the
information never goes public and then
we don't know what our government is
doing in our name and we have a right
it's and to me it's one of the most
important rights that that an American
can have the right to know what his
government is doing in his name
you
sorry I think we're getting a lot of
feedback from people that they're
finding it really powerful that we are
recognizing that this isn't a lift or a
right issue but this is a human a human
rights issue char oh my goodness yes
this is not at all an issue of left or
right this is specific to human rights
civil rights and civil liberties and and
it's not specific to the United States
certainly this is this is an
international issue I think we're headed
toward an international crisis if we
turn our backs on Julian Assange I know
what it's like to feel like you're
standing alone to feel like the entire
weight of the government is has fallen
on your head that there's nowhere to
turn there's nowhere to go I know
exactly what the man is going through
and it's terrible it's lonely and so
it's up to us to remind him and to
remind the world the broader audience
out there that we're with him that we
support him we support the organization
and we support the issue and that we
won't back down as so many people here
in the US have been cowed by these
ridiculous comments by senior US
government officials that WikiLeaks is
akin to a hostile foreign intelligence
service well the reason that they've
said that is because they're afraid of
it and they're afraid of the work that
WikiLeaks has done they're afraid
because WikiLeaks has been effective
let's compare WikiLeaks to the the
intercept for example I'm biased against
the intercept because two of the two of
the journalists there were I'll just say
it straight out they were responsible
for putting me in prison for two years
because they blew my identity to the
government blatantly they did the same
thing to reality winner they may have
done the same thing to this FBI agent
who came forward in Minneapolis
Minnesota
you can't trust a national security
journalist if that national security
journalist doesn't know how to protect
his national security services
I'm sorry sources but look at WikiLeaks
WikiLeaks has never blown a
national-security source never and
beyond protecting the sources identity
they have protected the sources in the
documents that they've released and
that's why this process takes time
because they're going through these
documents to make sure that nobody gets
in trouble that nobody's identity is
compromised
no no journalism outlet does anything
like that that's specific to wicker I
was tried there ed Snowden was charged
there Jeffrey sterling was charged there
we've all had our cases in the Eastern
District of Virginia there's one judge
in particular judge Leonie brinkema who
reserves all of these cases for herself
so she's been the judge for all of us
and we were all found guilty beyond that
she made it literally impossible to
mount a defense because every time we
would motion the court to allow us to
declassify information necessary to
defend ourselves she denied the motion
she denied seventy two of my motions and
have proved zero we were walking out of
the courtroom one day and I said to my
attorney what just happened and my
attorney said we just lost the case
that's what happened well Julian is
looking at the same kind of outcome if
he's forced out of that Embassy and
extradited to the United States he will
not he cannot get a fair trial it's
impossible because the deck is stacked
and everybody knows what's going to
happen if he comes back to the Eastern
District of Virginia this is the same
advice I gave that Snowden don't come
home because you can't get a fair trial
here Julian doesn't have the choice and
that's what frightens me even more
yeah and that's so important to hear
from you from your perspective on that I
think that's a really important
information for our audience to have
about what it is exactly that he faces
if he were to lose asylum or to walk out
of the embassy this would not be a fair
judicial process whatsoever so you know
thank you for explaining that oh sure
and we also have to remember that that
the the Brits are essentially puppets
of the united states in cases like this
they they will do anything that the US
intelligence community tells them to do
and I think we can all assume should
assume that the US has told the British
that as soon as Julian walks out of that
embassy that the US wants him yeah and I
believe recently after the first vigil
Cassandra actually tweeted an old leaked
picture of the orders that the police
guarding the embassy were given which
was to immediately arrest him
immediately put him into custody if he
came out even if he was somehow in I
believe the the document said that if he
was in a diplomatic bag or something
ridiculous like that but basically there
this is not a normal you know process
that he's going through and it would not
be a normal result if he were to leave
so no certainly not and his hands are
tied you know up until now I think all
of us believe that we could count on the
Ecuadorians I hope that we still can I
know that I know that President Correa
has expect as former President Correa
has expressed disappointment in in Linea
Moreno's policy toward Julian
I still hope that this policy is
temporary I know we all do definitely I
hope so as well I hope that with voices
like yours and all of the other voices
that are being raised whether it's you
know Roger Waters you know with this
concert all of these efforts I hope that
that will make a real difference for a
marina and his decision on this due to
John that point that you just brought up
before about how the last time we got
together for the first vigil have been
you were confident or you felt sure that
Julian's communications would be
restored I think I felt exactly the same
way and the reason that we actually
designed unity for Jay is in a new mass
movement and not just a continuation of
hash reconnect Julian is because we
actually thought to ourselves oh yeah
he'll be reconnected any day now but the
larger issues that we need to free him
from the embassy and we also we just
took it for granted that because
previously had been disconnected and
then reconnected that it was just a
matter of time but
looking at you know the geopolitical
situation and seeing as you're just
talking about Ecuador in the the
developments with Linda Marino it seems
that we might have I think there's a
it's a human tendency actually you know
we look at someone like Julian who goes
through so much who faces such vast
incredible forces and he seems to just
you know weather weather every storm and
take almost take it on the chin but we
know in reality it's not in reality he
is suffering severely is serious medical
conditions there's the his situation is
far more dire than you would know by
reading the mainstream media you know
and I'm thinking like how dangerous it
is that we would just take for granted
that he'd be reconnected and and that
seems like a huge danger to me yeah this
is a list of urgency we need to there is
an emergency that's right this is a
lesson that we we shouldn't take
anything for granted at this point and
and you raised a very important point to
this is a human rights issue relative to
his health and this is something that
really is not reported anywhere but the
man's health cannot be very good closed
up in that embassy 24 hours a day seven
days a week
he needs sunlight he needs exercise he
needs nutritious food and we have no
idea if he's getting any of that
well fortunately we do know that he said
that they're feeding him but there was
probably the most alarming statement
I've ever heard was out of one of his
legal team a few weeks ago who's
actually said there you know he faces
not even being able to see down the
hallway because his eyesight is
degrading so severely from only having
this tiny limited space he's he's
actually suffering organ damage and I
know from studying his medical reports
that his doctors have said that he's a
mortal risk
it's no joke he is literally at mortal
risk risk so how do we how do we
convince people of this how do we
humanize him John you know I think we
have to keep doing what we're doing and
we have to keep reminding everybody that
this is a human rights issue you know
the the mainstream media tends to not
cover Julian's story there might be an
update of a few sentences every once in
a while saying Julian Assange is still
in the Ecuadorian Embassy we need to
make sure that it's out there all the
time even if that's just in the
mainstream media for the time being I
have a I have a small radio show in in
Washington and we talk about Julian all
the time we interview people like Danny
burrito and and Randy credito for
example people who know Julian and have
seen him and have spoken to him because
we need that first-hand accounting of
his health and his spirits and any news
that he may have for us anything that he
has heard perhaps from the Ecuadorians
perhaps from his attorneys we need to
make sure that the information is out
there and people are reminded every day
that this is a very important issue and
it's very dangerous for Julian Assange
absolutely we did we did recently see a
series of pieces come out of the
Guardian it was the typical smear pieces
but at this time it was an entire series
of them and interestingly they were
based on anonymous sources but those
anonymous sources were leaking
information about intelligence agency
activities that had been actually in
defense of Julian providing security to
the embassy what's your take on that
John where it seems that leaking
information to the press is fine if
you're doing it to attack a
whistleblower rather than to be a
whistleblower oh welcome to my life you
know the the biggest leakers in
Washington are the White House the CIA
in the FBI that's been a fact of life
since the creation of those
organizations because this is what they
do they do it to control the story they
do it to control the debate they do it
to influence public opinion it's it's
only a leak if it's something that they
don't like if it's something that they
like it's authorized we see the same
thing with the Guardian and I have to
add to I've been very disappointed in
the Guardian you know the Guardian was
one of the recipients of of Julian's
largesse of information directly from
from WikiLeaks and to turn on him like
they have and what's supposed to be a
progressive paper is really very very
disappointing
I completely agree and that that uh
escalation of those six you know
articles on him was really shocking to
see I mean it really seemed like they
were just piling on and accusing him of
stuff that was absolutely ludicrous and
I thought it was great that we saw
WikiLeaks actually well yeah like say
that they were going to file a suit for
libel because it was so ridiculous
sorry agreed and what do you think that
that signifies that we see those pylons
like that do you think that that's
because you know from their perspective
they had to uh you know undo some of the
successful backlash this this gagging of
him which has as I said it's become a
backlash in terms of increasing support
for him do you think that was the main
the main goal with that or was it more -
yes we also have to remember that
intelligence services all around the
world are are well schooled in
psychological warfare and I think that
this is this is a concerted attempt a
formal attempt to to weaken Julian
mentally emotionally maybe even
physically and to to make him give up in
the end I think that's really the goal
you know they they can plant stories in
whatever media they want they put these
false narratives out there and people
are gullible they'll believe anything
they read in the press with the ultimate
result being Julian's weakening yeah I
think we can truly blame intelligence
services for this and be right John I'd
like you to game theory a little bit for
me um I think you can take the this
collaboration of intelligence services
with the Guardian and smearing Julian
Assange you could take it two ways one
is that the u.s. is now really on top of
the situation and they're like this far
away from getting their hands on Julian
and they're winning the media war that
there could be true or it could be and
this is what I suspect that they are
trying to depict that that is the case
and that they are hoping that by
depicting them
tells us being in this position of
incredible strength and ecuador is
collaborating with them that they will
be able to you know manifest the future
that they that they want to realize
rather than their actually being the
situation what does he take on that what
the the second scenario is entirely
plausible and the the reason why I
believe that it could be the case is
that you never hear any any complaints
really about WikiLeaks coming out of the
White House you remember during the
campaign Donald Trump said I love
WikiLeaks remember that I mean he was he
was grandstanding of course but slowly
definitely yeah well so we're not seeing
leaks coming from the Justice Department
we're not seeing leaks coming from the
White House the only things that we're
seeing are coming from the FBI and the
CIA and then we're seeing actually
public statements from former CIA
director Mike Pompeo so there may be a
policy split here that this is this is a
Tier one target or operation for the CIA
but it's really not very important for
the White House so your second scenario
may very well be the case but again
either way regardless of whether it's
the first scenario or the second one of
the goals is to weaken Julian and to
isolate Julian and that's what we really
have to push back on and we really don't
have much in the way of of ammunition
except papal power exactly because we
know that international law is on Julian
side we know that President is on Julian
side he has one and time and time again
in his legal battles against the
government's and kind of say agencies
that really governments that are
persecuting him and that arbitrarily
detaining him and I think what is going
to have to happen is is going to have to
be a mass movement an international
movement a la free Nelson Mandela
movement of the 80s to push it you know
to turn the tide to put enough pressure
on these governments that they will have
to abide by international law and that
they will have to free him John I'd like
to take you back and
a little bit I would actually like you
to take us back in time a little bit
from my perspective you are a hero
you're a celebrated whistleblower your
whistle blowing was of historic
proportions as I was saying earlier and
when I was discussing the fact you'd be
on stream your revelations made a US
president have to stand up an answer to
what was being done and there are very
few people on this planet that can say
that they've had that type of impact on
global affairs
he said if you just just a moment ago
though you were talking about feeling
isolated and feeling like the world was
against you and so I wondered can you
take us back in time to explain to us
tell us the story of that transition how
did you get from point a of being all by
yourself on your lonesome against the
most fearsome Intelligence Agency in the
world
arguably to being a household name and
celebrated as a hero and having your
whistleblowing recognized at the level
that it has been well on the on the day
that the FBI told me that they were
going to arrest me they actually
intended to arrest me that day and the
only thing that saved me was I said I
want to speak to my lawyer and I want to
speak to him right now that was on a
Thursday the FBI likes to arrest people
on Thursdays because the courts don't
arraign new prisoners on Fridays and so
you have to spend Thursday night Friday
night Saturday night and Sunday night in
jail and frankly they hope that you have
a rough time maybe you get beaten up it
softens you up a little bit and then
you're more willing to take a deal I'm
not exaggerating when I tell you that
every whistleblower who's facing prison
consider suicide it's just a natural
thing I've spoken to 50 different
whistleblowers and to a man and woman
every one of them considered committing
suicide in the very beginning it's that
terrible it's that difficult you really
feel that isolated but there were two
things that kind of
changed my perspective one was my wife
she told me a couple of days after my
arraignment on the following Monday they
have consistently underestimated your
strength you can you can take them she
said you have to fight them and she was
right I had to fight and I decided that
I would she also said that I had to own
my whistle blowing that I had done
nothing to be ashamed of I had done
something instead to be proud of and
that if I kept talking about it
eventually my side of the story would
become the side of record and the
government's story would disappear after
a while because they would move on to
their next victim who happened to be ed
Snowden and so I did keep talking about
it now when I first went to prison I was
just you know
prisoner number seven nine six eight 308
three I wasn't anybody and then I wrote
a letter an open letter to my attorneys
six weeks after I got to prison just to
tell them what the experience was like
up to that point I didn't even realize
that I was blowing the whistle on on
corruption inside the prison the prison
guards corruption it led to an inspector
general investigation in the Department
of Justice and my attorney sent it to
Arianna Huffington she put it on the
Huffington Post and it got more than a
million hits which was a real surprise
to me I I was I was getting interview
requests from everywhere from CNN and
Fox and and MSNBC and Time magazine The
Washington Post the New York Times it
was crazy about six weeks after that ed
Snowden went public with his revelations
and I wrote an open letter to him and I
followed it up with a private letter
that I sent through a mutual friend the
open letter received many millions of
hits and I realized then so it took me a
good six months I realized then that I
wasn't alone that there were a lot of
like-minded people out there I just
didn't realize it and
people started writing to me and I made
a decision on my very first day in
prison that if somebody was going to
take time out of their day to sit with a
pen and paper and write me a letter I
was going to answer that letter and I
ended up answering more than 7,000
letters in the 23 months that I was in
prison and again every letter that I
received was a reminder that I was not
alone that we were in this together and
you know we had a chance at success
because this was a real movement that is
absolutely incredible and I think it's
really really helpful for the audience
to hear that they've made such a
difference to receive those letters yeah
I think that that is really important
for people to understand and apply the
same to Julianne in this situation right
now I agree
write those letters it only takes a few
minutes just a few minutes you can't
imagine how much that'll bright is
brighten his day when he receives it and
knows that he's not alone absolutely
because yeah he wasn't he's not just
confined now to the embassy as we know
he's obviously in actually a solitary
confinement style situation so yeah you
know what let's second on that because
that's what this is this is solitary
confinement you know the United Nations
has declared solitary confinement as a
form of torture
absolutely solitary confinement just
because he happens to have a television
doesn't make it any less confining so
this is something that we need to to
remember the solitary confinement in
part is meant to break you mentally and
I don't care how tough you are or how
strong you are everybody is going to
break eventually
so our letters are gonna help keep him
steady and sane and focused it's up to
us to make sure that he's not forgotten
that human the human link there is so so
incredibly important and I it's
interesting that Suzy was mentioned here
tell you how wonderful that was because
you know for even just a few minutes you
forget that you're in a cage and that
you're being held under armed guard it's
surrounded by barbed wire fences and
guard towers it's liberating even just
for a few minutes so don't worry about
about trying to think up something
profound just just say hello and tell
them how your day is that's incredible
to hear I think that's really important
for people to hear because I know that a
lot of people Isuzu was saying earlier
they don't see us on jazz as a human
being like the rest of us they see it as
somebody who's kind of up on a pedestal
almost and we really have to understand
that he is a human being and he needs
connection to other human beings in
order to survive because we all do so
that's right
definitely so I'm gonna check chat
really fast and see if we have any
questions for you that are in the in
that chat one moment why look if you
guys have questions for John please let
us know and we will pass those on
immediately I'm really interested to
know how how are you yourself because
you're also in that same kind of
position where you lord it as a hero by
so so many people they look up to you so
much what you've done but at the end of
the day you know that you yourself
you're a normal guy got a family you got
a normal life you deal with the every
day-to-day struggles of you know every
person on the planet how do you have you
felt that disconnect between the way
that you depicted the image of you
versus your reality oh yeah most
definitely
I'm just a guy I'm just a normal guy
there's nothing special about me in any
way you know and I'm subject to the same
kind of pressures that everybody else
has maybe more because with my
conviction for example I lost my federal
pension and so I'm gonna have to work
until the day I die that's just a
reality Daniel Ellsberg told me one
thing one time that one thing that all
mister blowers have in common is that
they die broke that they're never able
to make a financial comeback after their
whistle blowing I'm determined that that
won't be me but you know as the years
begin to tick by since I first went
public I'm realizing that that may be me
so yeah I know
see myself as anything special
frankly I tried to not blow the whistle
I kept waiting for someone else to come
forward and nobody did so I finally said
something Wow you know who said that
word for word Snowden it's very true
that's very very very true yeah
and and the cost is very very high you
know it's not just financial but
personal to my wife finally had enough
and and she walked and I can't blame her
this dress is terrible
the pressure is unbearable sometimes so
yeah there's the counterbalance to that
like on one on one side we have the
price of the risk so that we take the
prices that we pay the horrific price
that we pay but on the other side of
that as Snowden says you can look
yourself in the mirror I say that every
day I'll tell you like four days before
I left for prison Jose Rodriguez the the
the Godfather of the CIA's torture
program the deputy director of the CIA
tweeted at me and he said don't drop the
soap [__] and I gave myself an hour
to cool off and then I tweeted back at
him and I said Jose I'm on the right
side of history and you are not and
left it at that and I know all these
years later that I was right I was right
and he was wrong and I know I can sleep
at night so it was worth it that is so
important to recognize and it's really
horrific how those types of people that
are so high up in the intelligence
community will take these really like
personal and ad hominem attacks at not
just yourself and not just
whistleblowers like Chelsea Manning but
also of course Julian Assange and
WikiLeaks its Ritz really it really
reveals their true nature I think when
we see it it really does there are a lot
of sociopaths walking around yeah
definitely I think that it's interesting
because I was just contemplating this
today actually about a certain CIA
ex-cia now state official who I won't
mention but I was actually contemplating
this very effective which is that in
their day to day life they have all
other cushy perks of having sold their
soul to the devil they have the nice
suits they have the big pay packets they
have the safety of knowing that they're
not going to be stalked and spied on and
targeted and smeared but when they go
home at night and they have to loot
themselves in the mirror
on some level I believe that they are
conscious that their power is derived
from the this apparatus that oppresses
and that destroys our planet it's not
they don't have any personal power
the only power they have in their life
comes from has been given them to them
or granted from them selling out to the
system they're selling them souls to the
system whereas whistleblowers and some
journalists are the opposite of that in
their day to day lives they don't have
the power
other than that they can derive from
their own speech and their own
self-worth they don't have the trappings
of power they don't that you know they
have to face the smears and the
hardships and as you say like the
financial ruin but then at nighttime
they can look themselves in the mirror
and they know that they didn't sell out
to the system they did
and they are not participating in the
destruction of the planet that and I was
very much contemplating that today
because we think of these and people is
these big scary figures these CIA you
know top CIA officials and whatnot but
it's the system that holds the power
it's not those people as individuals if
anything those people as individuals
have sold out their ability to have any
personal power to become an agent and
Agent Smith of the state and am i under
something you're laughing John so I must
be under something you're really onto
something that's that's quite true a
senior CIA former senior CIA official
told me just last week he's been retired
for I don't know a year year and a half
he told me that he had to go on an
antidepressant medication because on
Friday he was one of the most important
people in America and on Monday he was a
nobody because he had retired and he
can't handle being a nobody and so he's
been struggling with such profound
depression that he has to be medicated
wow that's a theme at the CIA they all
think that they're the most important
people in America because they they have
they have sort of self-appointed
jurisdiction over life and death for so
many people and then they trick
themselves into thinking that they're
irreplaceable and in fact they're very
replaceable absolutely
yeah the the groupthink that goes on in
the intelligence agencies that can be so
intense i I've read you know in
different different press reports that
it's so intense that it actually damages
their ability to function in some
instances is that something that you
have seen oh absolutely in fact one of
my attorneys Bruce Fein and I have been
talking about writing a book exactly
about that because if you look at the
the major international developments
over the last 70 years as the creation
of the CIA the CIA has been wrong about
just about every one of them and it's
it's because of that groupthink you know
they throw
these these these slogans and and
business buzzwords about thinking
outside the box and establishing a red
team or a tiger team and it's all
nonsense they don't know what they're
doing
in fact they end up sitting around the
conference room table and just agreeing
with one another that's incredible
that's amazing to hear like it's from
somebody who's really experienced it
that's really really interesting
thank you for sure just just respect to
the psyche issues thing it just reminds
me of the WikiLeaks group and I'm sure
that this is going to be one of the
reasons the CIA really has it in for
them WikiLeaks publishing the leaked
Brennan emails from his mouth comma
trace and end there was sure enough was
his psych reports from his he'd actually
been seeing a psychologist to deal with
the emotional fallout of being a
tyrannical CIA director so funny isn't
it you know CIA psychiatrist once told
me that the CIA and I say this is my
speeches all the time the CIA actively
seeks to hire people who have
sociopathic tendencies they try not to
hire sociopaths
because sociopaths have no conscience
and with no conscience they easily pass
a polygraph exam but they're impossible
to control because they don't feel guilt
people who have sociopathic tendencies
do have a conscience and do feel guilt
but are happy to work in moral ethical
and legal gray areas the problem is that
because sociopaths are sociopaths
they're gonna slip through the cracks
anyway and like in any corporate
environment it's the sociopaths who work
their way to the top and they work their
way to the top because they're also
happy to just climb over the backs of
their colleagues and co-workers to make
it to the top and that's how you end up
with John Brennan or a Jose Rodriguez or
a George Tenet because they actually are
sociopaths okay that makes so much sense
go ahead CG but then even these
sociopaths they aren't
and some much electing so much pain and
on this entire planet as well as people
on it they still seem to have at some
level this deep psychological fallout
and I find that quite fascinating
because it tells me that even though
they're conditioned to exhibiting this
psychopathic behavior at some level I
truly think that deep down in a little
box somewhere that they keep it hidden
in is this tiny scrap of conscience well
I personally disagree with that
completely but that's just my personal
take on that I think there are people
that are biologically different than
other people in that way but Oh step out
of that I hope Suzie's right I don't
know to tell you the truth but it seems
to me that that any normal person I mean
you can only kill so many people or be
responsible for the deaths of so many
people before something gets to you I
mean you've got to end up with with PTSD
or some kind of psychological malady
you can't just unless you're a true
sociopath and then you can just kill
with impunity and and go right to sleep
at night this is just I'm just bringing
this back to Julian as making this
discussion is making me reflect on the
fact that the CIA derives its power from
its ability to inflict violence and to
control people and Julian Assange has
derived his power from his ability to
save people for his ability to provide
them with the truth
the CIA derives power from lies from
their false Flags and their fate color
revolutions and their everything else
Julian and WikiLeaks have derived power
from truth-telling and that's why there
are such a threat because if there's one
thing that the CIA cannot abide that is
transparency
there are makes mo sense this that's the
house of cards right mm-hmm exactly
it can bring
the house of cards amazing that also
reminds me while we're getting into like
theory of stuff it reminds me of a
diagram that I saw it was a
counterinsurgency doctrine and it said
it's like the three pillars of society
and when was the financial one was the
police and one was the government and
these three pillars in a house formation
and on the bottom the foundation of the
house is information and information was
the only factor that had the capacity to
bring down all three pillars and they
said that each pillar on its own could
fall and the structure could remain so
you could have a total financial crash
but the police state the security stayed
in military and the government combined
would keep the house up you could have
you know lose your military force but
still the financial and the government
is enough to like rebuild that as we've
seen in many states that have had to
rebuild their security forces we could
have a you know lose the Prime Minister
the Prime Minister's to sit down the
government is dissolved but you still
have the police of military security
state needs to have the financial role
that the house stays up but the
information pool at the bottom when you
threaten that information pool you place
all three pillars in jeopardy and that
was the counterinsurgency doctrine oh I
believe every word of that I think
that's exactly right and years and years
of thought have gone into that doctrine
they know exactly what they're talking
about but again we have this leg in yang
where the CIA would use that doctrine to
destabilize a country they would use
information warfare to destabilize those
three pillars that are holding their
society together WikiLeaks is using
information to destabilize those who
would destabilize the society if that
makes sense here it's like they they are
almost like the inoculating force
WikiLeaks is like the inoculating force
to the virus absolutely right and that's
why we need wiki Li
because because there are no
journalistic outlets that have that kind
of power you know it only WikiLeaks does
the Washington Post isn't going to take
down the CIA or the New York Times or
The Guardian or the intercept only
WikiLeaks has that kind of authority and
leverage that's why we need a strong
WikiLeaks and that's why we need a free
Julian Assange exactly they had the
integrity that nobody else has nobody at
all so from your perspective how do
people what is some of the what are some
of the ways and I mean you know I know
we've hashed this up before but from
your unique perspective how can people
that are listening and watching you know
actively help you know help support
WikiLeaks and Julian Assange you know in
addition to the letter writing to keep
him you know connected to humanity what
are some of the things people can really
tangibly do to help that you that you
think of from what he done through I was
speaking to a member of Congress about a
week ago and the the topic of WikiLeaks
came up and this guy is a very
conservative Republican he's a member of
the tea party caucus here in the States
which is the it's a group of the most
conservative members of the House of
Representatives and he said that he had
sort of a knee-jerk reaction against
WikiLeaks for a long time until
constituents began to write to him and
to ask us to port WikiLeaks and so he
said he never really gave it much
thought until people began to write and
you know these guys really are
responsive to their constituents they
really are I've worked on both the house
side and the Senate side and I can tell
you that when people write letters to
their elected representatives they
listen and so he actually reevaluated
and reinstate reassessed his entire
position on WikiLeaks I'm not sure that
he's willing to say that publicly yet
but you know one at a time and over time
we can actually win this thing
I think that's a really really valuable
piece of information for people to have
because I know that when I give that
answer to people well you can write
letters to your representatives you can
write letters to so-and-so you know this
kind of that sense of
well that's not enough and people have
to understand how much of a real impact
that makes it's a big deal
truly absolutely so is there anything
else you want to talk to us about about
your experience with Julian Assange or
WikiLeaks or anything else related to
this whole issue I just wanted people to
understand go right ahead nor my audio
just cut out for a second I thought it
was his and then I realized it was mine
I'm sorry girlfriend right hey I just
wanted to say that I'm genuinely worried
about Julian
you know I before they cut off his
communication his access to the outside
world I wasn't really worried about him
and I thought well you know eventually
this thing is going to play out and he's
gonna end up being fine and something's
gonna happen
they're gonna drop the charges and
they're not gonna charge him in the
first place or the Brits are gonna walk
away or whatever I'm worried now I'm
worried because I really believed for a
long time that we could count on the
Ecuadorians and I'm not sure that's the
case anymore so I feel like there's a
sense of urgency or immediacy and we
need to we need to pull together and be
active now more than we ever have in the
past
I completely agree I think it's so
important to hear that they hear I
understand that message definitely I'm
from your perspective what was the most
significant I mean WikiLeaks has got
dozens of significant publications but
what was there anything that if he you
was deeply personally significant yeah
you know in in the Snowden revelations
the the notion that that the American
government was spying on its own
citizens I think most people don't
understand the full significance of that
information the NSA and CIA are
forbidden by law from spying on
Americans NSA's Charter actually
prohibits it from spying on Americans
but that's exactly what they were doing
using 9/11 as an excuse using the
Patriot Act as a justification it was
only because of Snowden's revelations
that a the American people became aware
of what was happening and be members of
Congress began realizing that this thing
is starting to spin out of control and
so it's just now in the last
year-and-a-half
that Congress has begun to reject
certain provisions of the Patriot Act
they've just begun to weaken parts of it
so we're not we can't call it a victory
yet but we're headed in that direction
and that's only because of Ed Snowden
and WikiLeaks I find it fascinating what
you were just saying that members of
Congress actually are responsive because
I remember when courage Foundation was
urging supporters of law read loved to
reach out to members of UK Parliament
and I actually thought to myself quite
cynically you know nothing gets the
effort but I thought to myself I will
any of these politicians even care you
know what's the chance of them like
reading the leaders and then sure enough
courage was able to drum up like some
phenomenal amounts of impose it like 60
or 70 some huge amount of politicians
and actually managed to
get them to advocate for lorry and I
think it very much was a deciding factor
in that case and the successful outcome
of Laurie's case you know a dozen House
members and two senators wrote to the
Bureau of Prisons inquiring about my
well-being and threatening them to not
put me in what was called diesel therapy
which was to transfer me to different
prisons around the country to silence me
and it was only because people were
writing letters to their congressmen
these congressmen really are receptive
they really are reactive to it that's
amazing
yes go ahead well how do we leverage
that how do we would liverish that for
gillian you know um there's something to
be said for a good old-fashioned
letter-writing campaign they're they're
important especially especially if
you're writing to people who actually
represent you for example I live in
Virginia if I write to a senator from
South Dakota he's not gonna care or a
congressman from South Dakota but if
somebody from South Dakota writes
they're gonna jump to attention and I
can write to my representatives here in
Virginia and they will jump to attention
so if we've got a concerted nationwide
or semi nationwide campaign going we can
really get results that way you know
we've just had a question from the
YouTube live chat and they've said why
did Obama believe his legacy would be
enhanced by his commutation of Chelsea's
sentence and that is synchronous I can't
even say the word it synchronizes with
the thought that I was just having which
is remembering that WikiLeaks had you're
just talking about the power of a good
old-fashioned letter writing campaign
that WikiLeaks actually did letter
writing campaigns to Obama on Chelsea
Manning's behalf the years before the
eventual commutation so what what would
be your response to that question about
why why do you think that Obama did go
ahead and commute the sentence I
actually
the answer from inside Obama's head and
I'll tell you why a very wealthy Greek
American businessman who is very
personally close to Joe Biden approached
Biden to ask him if he would ask Obama
to pardon me and so I went to Delaware
one night I took the train and went to
Biden's house and this Greek American
took the train down from New York and we
met at Biden's house and Biden agreed to
go to the president the next night and
lobby for me so the next day the two of
them went to the White House I went home
I wasn't invited to the White House and
and when they came out the Greek
American businessman called me and he
said you would have been so proud of Joe
Biden he went to the mat for you
he argued your case with everything that
he had and then he said ten minutes into
it the president put up his hands and
said guys I'm just not going to do this
it's either him or it's Manning and
Manning got thirty five years and that's
why Obama did it Obama was not upset
that Chelsea was convicted Obama just
believed that 35 was too much so he
didn't really commute Chelsea's sentence
out of the goodness of his heart
or because of some some you know pursuit
of justice I mean we all know now that
Barack Obama was the enemy of
transparency he waged a war on
whistleblowers Chelsea just got lucky in
the end yeah that is something that a
lot of people underestimate and don't
take into account is how much Obama
actually escalated a lot of these
problems he was persecuted eight
national security whistleblowers that's
almost three times the number of all
previous presidents combined extremely
just mind-boggling that a supposedly
liberal president would do that type of
thing and it really kind of reveals that
it's not just you know it's not New York
on one side of the political spectrum
this is obviously an unelected power
structure that persists despite whoever
is elected president
and that that's that's the power that as
you've been saying Julian Assange is up
against right now and that is what is so
disturbing and I think as you mentioned
that's what overrides the fact you know
whatever comments Trump may have made on
the campaign trail that own alleged
power structure has it has its own
agenda sir yep let me let me leave you
with one thought I know my time is up
it's not looking fine you're gonna fine
me leave you with one more thought
there's a pardon process a formal pardon
process here in the states it's both
pardon and commutation in brock obama's
final two years as president the u.s.
pardon attorney recommended zero people
for a partner zero there were lots of
commutations but nobody was pardoned in
the last two years so you know you're
right it doesn't matter if you're
liberal or conservative or neo liberal
or neo conservative it makes no
difference we have to elect people
regardless of party for whom civil
rights and civil liberties and human
rights are important because the the the
deep state or the federal bureaucracy
whatever you want to call it isn't gonna
do it for us that's an incredibly
important you know statement and it's a
great one to leave everyone with thank
you so much for joining us best of luck
tonight thank you it's an honor to speak
with you and happy here was all mine
thanks for inviting me thank you so much
John we are so so lucky to have you I
just want to thank you too from the
bottom my heart it's a really special to
speak with you is amazing thank you so
much it's great to Julian absolutely
absolutely thank you